Congratulations!
恭喜！
You've implemented your first algorithm that can solve an MDP.
你已经实现了可以解决 MDP 的首个算法
For the remainder of this lesson,
在这节课的剩余时间内
we'll look at some variations of this algorithm,
我们将讨论该算法的一些变体形式
and you'll have the chance to implement all of them to compare their performance.
你将有机会实现所有这些算法并比较它们的效果
We'll begin by looking at this policy evaluation step.
首先 我们将查看这个策略评估步骤
Remember that policy evaluation is
注意 策略评估是一种迭代算法
an iterative algorithm where we rely on a Bellman update rule.
并依赖于贝尔曼更新规则
The number of iterations needed for a single round of
完成一轮策略评估所需的迭代次数
policy evaluation is decided according to some small positive number theta that you set.
由你所设置的小数字 θ 决定
And the closer you wanted your approximate state by
要使你的估算状态值函数
your function to the true value function,
与真正的值函数越接近
the smaller you had to make this hyperparameter theta.
就要使这个超参数 θ 越小
But now the question is,
现在的问题是
can we sacrifice some accuracy here?
这里能够牺牲一定的准确性吗？
After all, who's to say how long this policy evaluation algorithm should take.
毕竟谁可以决定这个策略评估算法应该持续多久呢
Smaller theta means it will take longer,
θ 越小 时长越久
but exactly how much longer will depend on your MDP.
但是具体多久取决于你的 MDP
Maybe, instead of terminating the algorithm with this stopping criterion,
或许我们不再使用这个停止条件终止算法
we can give an absolute number of iterations that were willing to calculate.
而是设定我们愿意计算的绝对迭代次数
So we could modify this policy evaluation step to
我们可以修改这个策略评估步骤
instead terminate after updating the values of each of the states,
在更新所有状态的值 1 次 2 次
maybe once, twice, or some positive integer number of times.
或次数达到某个正整数后 终止该算法
The idea is that if our goal is to get an optimal policy,
原理是如果我们的目标是获得最优策略
we aren't prevented from doing that by having a value function that's a little bit off,
那么我们可以使用一个不太接近的值函数
so we don't need to wait for a really good estimate of
因此我们不需要完全等待准确地估算出值函数
the value function before calculating an improved policy.
才去计算优化的策略
For instance, say this is the optimal actual value function for a hypothetical MDP.
例如 假设这是虚拟 MDP 的最优动作值函数
One optimal policy then can be obtained by looking at each state separately,
我们可以通过单独查看每个状态获得一个最优策略
and then picking the action that maximizes the function.
然后选择最大化该函数的动作
But say we don't have this optimal action value function,
假设我们没有这个最优动作值函数
say instead we're working with a wildly incorrect estimate,
我们使用的是估算很不正确的函数
where all the values are way off,
所有值都偏差很大
but the relative values between many state action pairs are correct.
但是很多状态动作对之间的相对值正确
Then if we use this technically incorrect value function to obtain a policy,
然后 如果我们使用这个严格意义上来说不正确的值函数来获得一个策略
that policy will in fact be the same optimal policy,
该策略实际上是相同的最优策略
but that's just the main idea.
这就是主要原理
We don't need to have
我们不需要一个完美或几乎完美的
a perfect or even near perfect estimate of the value function to get an optimal policy.
值函数逼近结果才能获得最优策略